The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
What the hell is going on?
一体どうなってるんだ
What happened?!
何が起きたんだろ
I don't know.
知らないわよ
マスタング大佐が
I heard Colonel Mustang did something.
何かやらかしたって噂だぜ
Are you serious?
それ　ほんとか
Well, it's just a rumor I heard.
あくまで噂だ
Hey! Turn on the radio!
ラジオつけろ　ラジオ
"Radio Capital"!
ラジオ·キャピタルだ
Radio Capital?
ラジオ·キャピタル
Yeah! There's something crazy going on!
すごいことになってんだよ
That station is so lame.
あの局　つまんないんだよなぁ
いいから　軍に放送を止められる前に　早く
Just do it!
Before the military stops the broadcast!
Hurry!
Is that right, Madam?
ということでしょうか
大総統夫人
The Führer President's wife?
Yes.
The Central Army tried to murder me.
中央軍は私を殺そうとしたのです
So they pointed a gun at you to shoot you dead?
すると　夫人に銃を向け
射殺の意思を示したと
That's right.
そうです
He said, "Kill her along with Colonel Mustang's men."
「マスタング大佐の部下ともども
撃ち殺してよし」と言われました
I've heard that Führer President Bradley is currently in the east for an inspection,
ブラッドレイ大総統は
東部の視察に行っていて  今は
and is not in Central at the moment.
セントラルには不在とのことですが
Yes.
So do you suppose someone in the upper echelon
では　閣下のいないときを見計らって
is planning a coup d'etat while the Führer President is absent?
中枢の誰かがクーデターを
I can't say for sure.
それは分かりません
Is this truly the real Madam?
この夫人って　本物か
I recognize this voice, though. She's real.
声　聞いたことあるぜ　本物だよ
But Madam, the fact that your son was also not in Central at the time is...
この状況下
ご子息がセントラルを離れていたのは…
息子とも連絡が取れないのです
I can't get in touch with my son either!
What?!
なんですって
You've gotta be kidding me!
うそだろ
Poor thing...
かわいそう…
I hope Selim's safe and sound.
セリム坊ちゃん　大丈夫かな
Please get yourself together, Madam Bradley.
気を確かに　ブラッドレイ夫人
A coup d'etat, they say!
クーデターだって
In any case, we are thankful that you're safe and sound.
Do you think anyone other than Bradley would be able to keep this nation together?
ブラッドレイ以外のヤツが
この国をまとめられるのかねぇ
If Colonel Mustang hadn't saved me,
I don't even know if I'd be here right now...
本当にマスタング大佐に
助けてもらわなければ
私もどうなっていたことか…
I see, so Colonel Mustang had already predicted the coup d'etat.
なるほど　マスタング大佐は
クーデターを察知していたと…
Mustang, huh...?
マスタングか…
Well then, could you please describe in detail of what happened when you were rescued?
それでは助け出されたときの状況を
詳しくお話願えますか
Of course.
はい
Have you still not told her that Selim is a homunculus?
セリムが人造人間だってこと
A gun was pointed at me, so I closed my eyes and began saying my prayers to God.
まだ夫人に教えてないの
How could we?
言えませんよ
She doesn't even know that her husband is currently missing.
大総統が行方不明だってことも
When I heard a gun go off, I thought everything was over.
知らないんですから
But-
ですが…
We hadn't told you this yet, Madam,
夫人にはまだ
お伝えしていなかったのですが
but the thing is, the train that the Führer President was on yesterday in the east was bombed by someone.
実は昨日
東で大総統の乗った列車が
何者かに爆破されました
What?
He is currently missing.
閣下は行方不明になっているのです
Madam Bradley!
ブラッドレイ夫人
Are you all right?!
大丈夫ですか
I-It appears as though Madam Bradley is feeling ill due to shock.
いっ　今　あまりのことに
ブラッドレイ夫人が気分を
悪くされてしまったようです
But the Führer President has gone missing?
What could this mean?
しかし　大総統閣下が行方不明とは
どういうことなのでしょう
Colonel Mustang has always been leery of the upper echelon,
マスタング大佐は以前から
上層部に不信感を抱き
and was anticipating that they'd pull something.
何か事を起こすのではと
危惧しておりました
And that's when the Führer President's train was bombed,
そこに大総統の列車爆破
and on top of that, an order to shoot the Madam was given.
更に　今回の夫人に対する発砲許可の件
Everything is clear now.
これではっきりしました
There is a faction in the upper echelon that wants to get rid of the Führer President.
上層部に
閣下を排除しようとする一派がいると
Fool!
バカ者　今すぐ放送を止めろ
Hurry up and stop the broadcast!
Be well-prepared for the consequences if you refuse!
さもないと　どうなるか
分かっているだろうな
But we can't!
そんなこと言われましても  無理です…
They've taken hostages, and we can hardly move due to the fact that they've got a gun on us!
人質を取られていますし
我々も銃を突きつけられて
身動き一つ取れません
And for starters, there are so many of them that we don't know what to do!
第一　犯人の数が多すぎて
どうにもなりませんて…
Let me talk to Mustang!
マスタングを出せ
I'll talk to him directly!
私が直接話をする
Huh?
The... Colonel?
大佐…ですか
Don't shoot!
撃たないで
Forgive me! Please!
許して　お願いします
How did you like my acting?
こんなんで　どうだ
It was perfect!
ばっちりです
Okay, keep the show airing!
よっしゃ　放送止めんな
はい
Sir!
Like we can let a scoop like this go!
こんな　すげぇネタ逃してたまるかっての
Next, we will have one of Colonel Mustang's subordinates speak with us.
では　続きまして
夫人救出に参加した
マスタング大佐の部下の方からの…
She also participated in the mission to rescue the Madam.
So it wasn't the Colonel who planned the coup d'etat.
大佐がクーデターを
謀ったわけじゃないのか
We, who support Colonel Mustang, have very little influence...
マスタング大佐に賛同する我々は
微力ではありますが…
この…声
This... voice!
...but inheriting the Führer President's will,
we are prepared to stand up to our underhanded opponents with everything we've got,
正義の名の下　卑劣な輩に
全力で立ち向かう覚悟であります
in the name of justice.
有り難うございました
That damned Mustang.
マスタングめ　ブラッドレイが
Now that Bradley isn't around, he's exploiting the hell out of the Führer President's influence.
いないのをいいことに
大総統の威光を使いたい放題だねぇ
And bringing up words like 'justice'...
しかも　正義などと
It would be nice if the people would take his bait.
国民が食いついてくれるといいけどねぇ
You sounded like you're used to this kind of stuff.
手慣れたもんだな
I'm surprised you could use a silly and vague word like 'justice'.
正義なんて　曖昧で浮ついた言葉
よく言うぜ
It's fine.
いいのよ
Everyone loves justice.
みんな大好きなんだから　正義が
She's right.
だな　先に言った者勝ちだ
The first person to say it wins.
What the hell is going on?
一体　どうなってんだ
I heard it's not Mustang and his men's doing.
マスタングたちの仕業じゃないらしいぞ
Is that really true?
ほんとかなぁ
Roy Mustang is telling the truth.
ロイ·マスタングの言うとおりだよ
We just arrived here from the east,
わしらは東から来たばかりだが
but there was a huge ruckus over there
about the Führer President's train being blown up.
あっちでは大総統の列車が爆破されたって
えらい騒ぎだった
Do the people at Central still not know about it?
セントラルの人たちは
まだこのことを知らないのかい
The highest-ranking man in the nation is missing, and they still haven't bothered to tell its people anything?
国のトップが行方不明なのに
市民にはなんの情報も出さないなんて
So it really is a coup d'etat?!
じゃあ　本当にクーデターかよ
Who's the mastermind?
誰が首謀者だ
If Radio Capital happens to be ambushed and the Madam gets killed,
これでラジオ·キャピタルが襲撃されて
夫人が死んだりしたら
it's obviously the upper echelon who's behind it all!
間違いなく上層部が黒だろ
セリムはどうした　セリムは
What happened to Selim?!
He's probably being taken hostage!
きっと　人質に取られたんだわ
殺されてなきゃいいけど…
I hope he's still alive...
What the hell are the guards doing?!
何をやっとるんだ　守備隊は
Sir!
Apparently, the enemy was in possession of more firearms than they'd expected,
敵が予想外に
大量の武器を所持していたらしく
and they're putting up a bitter fight.
苦戦を強いられていると
There has to be limit to how many firearms they can carry!
武器ったって
持ち運べるものなど
たかが知れとるだろう
We have a call from the guards.
守備隊から通信です
Here, sir.
どうぞ
What took you so long to contact us?!
連絡が遅い
What is going on over there?!
そっちはどうなっている  どうぞ
Over!
W-We had no idea the men from Briggs were in possession of such-
ブ…ブリッグズのヤツら
あんなものまで…
H-Hey!
W-Will we be okay?
だ…大丈夫でしょうか
There's no way they'll take control of this place, right?
ここが落とされるなんてことは
ないでしょうね
Of course!
当たり前だ
Seriously... what fools.
ったく　バカバカしい
They're going to have to bring in something like a tank to-
戦車でも　持ってこないかぎりここは…
Huh?
What?!
何ぃ
Shall I lend you a hand, Fullmetal?
手を貸した方がいいかね　鋼の
Colonel!
大佐
Looks like you've made some new friends.
何やら　新しい仲間も
増えているようだが…
Scar.
スカー
But wow, this place brings back memories, Lieutenant.
しかし　懐かしい場所だな　中尉
It reminds me of your crying face.
君の泣き顔が思い出される
I'd like to see honest tears like that from you again someday.
また　ああいう素直な涙を見たいものだ
I thought you despised liquids.
水分は大嫌いなんじゃないですか
Since they make you useless.
無能になるから
Save the chatting for later!
無駄話はあとにしろ　戦え
Take them down!
Don't you order me around!
貴様が命令するな
了解
Roger!
We need to defeat these pale things, right?
この白いのを倒せばいいのね
It's useless, Lieutenant!
無理だ　中尉
Bullets aren't enough to bring them down!
こいつらは銃弾じゃ倒せない
That again?!
また　そんなのばっかり
Why does this always happen?
Homunculi?
人造人間
No, their wounds aren't recovering.
いや　自己修復をしていない
But they don't die.
だが死なない　賢者の石の力か
Must be the power of a philosopher's stone.
They are enemies, Fullmetal.
これは敵だ　鋼の
Running around like a cockroach...!
この　ちょろちょろと
Seems like he doesn't want me going this way.
どうやら　こっちには
行ってほしくないようですね
気配も強くなります　やはり…
That sensation also grows larger as I go...
It has to be...!
Is that you, May?!
メイか
Envy!
エンヴィー
You guys...!
お前ら…
Fool!
バカ者　なぜ国へ帰らなかった
Why didn't you return to your country?!
But...
でも…だって　だって…
B-
Because...!
もういい　泣くな
It's fine. Don't cry.
I'm so sorry, Mister Scar!
ごめんなさい　スカーさん…
Man...
ったく　人間のそういうの
Human traits like this make my skin crawl.
虫ずが走るんだよね
But wow, looks like you guys showed them who's boss.
それにしても
よくもまあやってくれたもんだよ
The Fullmetal Alchemist and the Flame Alchemist.
鋼の錬金術師に焔の錬金術師
In addition, Scar.
それに　スカー
The shitty chimeras I owe a favor to from up north are with you too.
北でお世話になった
クソ合成獣どもも一緒か
Now... I wonder who I should take care of first.
さて  どいつから片づけてやろうか
お前がエンヴィーか
So you're Envy?
You're the Homunculus that can change form, right?
確か　変身できる人造人間だったな
Oh, you know about me?
知ってるんだ
Nice to meet you, Colonel Mustang.
はじめまして　マスタング大佐
Wait, huh?
っと　あれっ
Is this okay, Scar?
いいのかい　スカー
He's a State Alchemist who turned Ishbal into hell.
こいつ　イシュヴァールを地獄にした
国家錬金術師だよ
You're right.
そうだな
What, you're all buddy-buddy now?
なれ合い
This is boring.
つまんないなぁ
Show me something more muddy and disgusting.
もっと  ドロドロしたもの見せてよ
I find enjoyment in watching you pieces of trash shrieking like animals.
あんたらゴミ虫がぎゃんぎゃん
わめいてるのが面白いのにさぁ
I don't have time to entertain your vulgar hobbies.
貴様のゲスな趣味に
つきあっている暇はない
Vulgar?
ゲス　じゃあ　聞くけどさ
Well then, let me ask.
Don't you humans also love watching people's unhappiness and watching fools dance?
あんたら人間だって
人の不幸とか
愚か者が踊るのを見てるのが
大好きなんじゃない
Isn't that why you're always fighting wars?
だから　しょっちゅう
戦争してるんじゃないの
True, it is indeed entertaining to watch fools dance like madmen.
確かに　愚か者が
踊り狂ってるのを見るのは愉快だ
It's especially entertaining to watch fools like you homunculi dance.
特に　人造人間とかいう愚か者が
踊り狂うさまを見るのは最高だ
Well, I answered your question.
貴様の質問には答えた
Now it's time for you to answer mine.
今度は私の質問に答えてもらおう
Who killed Maes Hughes?
マース·ヒューズを殺したのは誰だ
Answer me, Homunculus.
答えろ　人造人間
Maria Ross.
マリア·ロスだよ
The one you burned to a crisp.
あんたが焼き殺した
Wrong.
違う　彼女ではなかった
It wasn't her.
So you basically burned an innocent woman alive?!
じゃあ　無実の女
生きたまま焼き殺したんだ　あんた
Nice one!
やるねぇ　ひどいねぇ
You're terrible!
So, how did you explain it to her family?
で　家族にはどう説明したの
Did you cry and beg for mercy?
泣いて謝った
Or did you perhaps refrain from saying anything because you were afraid of how furious they'd be?
それとも怒られるのが嫌で黙ってた
Were you never taught to shut your mouth, moron?!
ベラベラとうるさいぞ　バカ
I'm starting to get tired of asking you homunculi the same question.
貴様ら人造人間に
この質問をするのも
いいかげん飽きてきた
Simply state the truth,
さっさと事実だけを答えろ  このバカ
you moron!
Who killed Hughes?
ヒューズを殺したのは誰だ
Congratulations, Colonel Mustang!
おめでとう　マスタング大佐
You finally found the real culprit.
やっと　たどりついたってわけだ
I can't imagine Hughes getting killed by a moron like you.
貴様のようなバカに
ヒューズが殺られるとは思えん
バカ
'Moron'?
Morons are what you'd call...
バカっていうのはさぁ
...idiots like Hughes...
こういう手に引っ掛かる…
...who'd fall for dumb shit like this!
ヒューズみたいなヤツのことをいうんだよ
Your face changed!
顔色が変わった
I love that expression!
いいね　その表情
Hughes had a great look on his face when I killed him too!
ヒューズを殺したときも最高だった
Yeah, that face!
あいつ　あの顔
The despair of being killed by someone who looks just like his beloved wife...
愛する妻の顔したヤツに
撃ち殺される絶望…
It was just...
もう　最っ高
...the best!
It's decided.
決まりだ
You're the one who killed Hughes.
貴様がヒューズを殺した
That's all I needed to know.
その事実さえ分かればよい
You don't need to say anything else, Envy.
もう　しゃべらなくていいぞ
エンヴィー
Let's start this by...
まず　その舌の根から…
...reducing your tongue to ashes.
焼き尽くしてやろう
Scar.
スカー　鋼の　ここは私に預けろ
Fullmetal.
Leave this place to me.
こいつは私の獲物だ
He's my prey.
G-Gotcha.
わ…分かった
Well then, we'll leave this place to you and go on-
じゃあ　ここは任せて
オレたちは先に…
Who gave you permission to pass?
誰が通っていいって言ったんだよ
I still need to repay the debt you guys gave me up north-
お前らには北でのお礼をたっぷり…
Do you have the time to be speaking to others while facing me?
この私の前でほかのヤツと
しゃべっている余裕があるのか
Seems like there's quite a lot of fat on that blabbering tongue of yours.
ベラベラと回転のいい　その舌には
よほどの脂がのっているとみえる
It burns quite well, Envy.
よく燃えるじゃないか　エンヴィー
Lieutenant, will it really be okay-
中尉　本当に二人だけで…
行って　エドワード君
Go, Edward.
We'll figure something out.
なんとかしてみせるわ
But...
だけど…
Go, Edward Elric.
行け　エドワード·エルリック
Don't you have something you need to take care of?
お前にはやるべきことがあるはずだ
おらっ　行くぞ　エド
Come on, let's go, Ed.
Hey-
ちょっと…
You son of a....!
くっそ…
The Colonel will be fine.
大佐なら大丈夫だ
Finishing off a homunculus
should be a piece of cake for him.
人造人間なんざ
ひとひねりにしてくれるって
That's not the issue I'm worried about.
そういう問題じゃねぇんだよ
Huh?
Then what is?
なんのこった
I see, so you've been seeking revenge for Hughes' death the entire time.
そう…ずっとヒューズの敵を追ってたんだ
What a beautiful friendship!
美しい友情だねぇ
Stay back, Lieutenant.
下がっていろ　中尉
Out of respect for that beautiful friendship, I'll fight you seriously.
その美しい友情に敬意を表して
本気で相手してやるよ
But I can't really hold back when fighting in this state.
でもこの体
手加減が利かないからなぁ
Don't blame me for any-
どうなっても知らな…
How does it feel to have all the liquids within your eyes boil?
眼球内の水分が沸騰する気分はどうだ
The pain goes far beyond anything you could possibly imagine, doesn't it.
想像を絶する痛みだろ
You little-
貴様…
It was nice of you to make yourself a bigger target.
わざわざ的を大きくしてくれるとは
Did you think you could beat me if you increased your size?
でかければ　勝てるとでも思ったか
Moron.
バカが
Get up, monster.
立て　化け物　さっさと再生しろ
Hurry up and regenerate.
I'll have you repeat this suffering until you're dead.
死ぬまでその苦しみを繰り返してやる
That's...
そうだ…そうだよ
That's right.
He's the one who burned Lust to death!
こいつはラストを焼き殺した男だ
Wait!
待て
Colonel!
大佐
You wait here, Lieutenant!
中尉はここで待っていろ
I'll dispose of him on my own!
あれは私一人で片づける
Yeah, I think it's this way.
こっち　たぶん　こっちです
These things look creepy.
気色悪いな
血管みたいだ
They're almost like veins.
I keep having this nasty feeling, like I'm having heartburn.
なんかさっきから胸焼けみたいな
いやな感じがするんだが…
Not surprising.
でしょうね　この奥
There's a huge cluster of energy ahead.
とてつもない気の塊がいます
Cluster of energy?
気の塊
Would you get it if I described it as an insane number of people crawling about?
ものすごい数の人がうごめいている感じ
と言ったら分かりますか
Not really, but I do understand that it feels disgusting.
なんか分からんが
気色悪い感じってのは分かる
I'd hate to encounter an enemy in a place like this.
こんな所で敵に遭遇したくねぇな
Scar, do you mind?
スカー　ちょっといいか
Is this about the Flame Alchemist?
焔の錬金術師のことか
Because I once lost my soul after engulfing myself in flames of revenge, I can understand well.
かつて復讐の炎に身を焼かれ
自分を見失ったオレにはよく分かる
If he goes on...
あの男　あのままでは
憎しみの炎で
...he'll end up reducing even his own heart with the flames of wrath.
己の心をも焼き尽くすだろう
Where did you go, Envy?!
どこだ　エンヴィー
Damn him...!
くそっ
出てこなければ
If you don't come out, you'll be seeing another huge explosion from me!
更に大爆発をぶちかますぞ
Yo, Roy.
ロイ
You're human after all! Let this throw you into confusion!
しょせん人間　混乱してろ
You'd set your best friend aflame without hesitation?!
親友をなんのためらいもなく焼くのか
Hughes is dead.
ヒューズは死んだ　もういない
He's no longer here.
Your actions do nothing more than feeding oil to flames!
貴様の行為は火に油を注ぐだけだ
Damn you!!
くそぉ  調子に乗ってんじゃねぇ
Don't get so cocky!!
Again...!
また目が…目が
My eyes... My eyes...!
愚かしい
Fool.
You came at me, thinking I wouldn't use much firepower if you were near me?
大火力は自分のそばでは
使わないと思ったか
Unfortunately for you, I can pinpoint.
あいにく　ピンポイントで狙える
Don't you dare underestimate me!
私の技を見くびるな
Colonel, I'm going to have to disobey your orders.
大佐　命令に背きます
また逃げたか
He ran away again.
You're disobeying my orders, Lieutenant.
命令違反だぞ  中尉
I apologize.
すみません
But I couldn't just stand there and wait...
でも  黙って待っているわけには…
Where is Envy?
エンヴィーは
I lost him.
見失った　ここはまるで迷路だ
This place is like a maze.
Don't leave my side, Lieutenant.
私のそばを離れるなよ　中尉
来たからには手伝ってもらう
Now that you're here, I'm going to ask for your help.
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
From the moment someone is born,
生まれた瞬間から
長い歳月を経て
they gradually become more and more human as time goes by.
人は人になっていく
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
積み重ねられたものはやがて
And what has been accumulated eventually becomes complete as a strong self.
堅牢な自我として
完成される
However...
だが…
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第５４話　『烈火の先に』
Episode 54, Beyond the Inferno.
Peer once more at your heart.
見つめ直せ　己の心を